Mss.B.H357.p
American Philosophical Society
Victor (Victor George) Heiser papers, ca. 1890-1972
Circa 1890-1972
Mss.B.H357.p
American Philosophical Society
25.0 Linear feet Ca. 25,000 items
There is much correspondence, as well as reports, notebooks, lectures, diaries, photographs, and reprints. Heiser, who was a preeminent public health physician, created a rich archive of material documenting all phases of his career, especially the international health work of the Rockefeller Foundation from 1913-1934. There are voluminous, detailed, and interesting diaries for the whole course of this life (ca. 68 v., 1908-1972). There are notebooks reflecting on his early training and work (21 v., 1890-1907), and 3 volumes from lectures he attended at Jefferson Medical College in Philadelphia (grad., 1898).
Ca. 25,000 items.
Heiser, Victor, (Victor George)
Box 1-50
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift from George Victor Heiser and accessioned, 1966 (1966 952ms). Ca. 7500 items presented by Heiser estate and accessioned, 12/07/1972 (1972 2313ms); interviews and diaries presented by Heiser estate and accessioned, 1972 (1972 1062ms, 1062.ams).
Custodial History note
Presented by Victor George Heiser and his estate, 1966-1972.
Biographical/Historical note
Victor George Heiser was a physician and was involved in international health work with the Rockefeller Foundation.
American Medical Association.; American Red Cross. Italian Commission of 1917.; Appleman, Leighton F.; Buck, Pearl S., (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973; Burrows, Samuel J.; Carpenter, Frank W., (Frank Watson), 1871-1945; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955; Emerson, Haven, 1874-1957; Epstein, Max, 1875-1954; Flexner, Abraham, 1866-1959; Forbes, W. Cameron, (William Cameron), 1870-1959; Harrison, Francis Burton, 1873-1957; Jefferson Medical College.; Lambert, S. M., (Sylvester Maxwell), 1882-; Miller, Fred D.; National Association of Manufacturers (U.S.); Phinney, Charles H.; Rockefeller Foundation.; Rockefeller, John D., (John Davison), 1874-1960; Rose, Wickliffe, 1862-1931; United States. Public Health Service.; University of the Philippines.; Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927; Asia, Southeastern -- Politics and government.; Asia, Southeastern -- Social conditions.; Aztec calendar; Banana plants--Central America; Central America -- Politics and government.; Central America -- Social conditions.; China -- Politics and government.; China -- Social conditions.; Diaries.; Gelatin silver prints; Indians of Central America--Languages--Writing; Industrial hygiene -- United States.; Italy -- History -- 1914-1922.; Leprosy.; Letterbooks.; Mayan languages--Writing; Medical care -- Asia, Southeastern.; Medical care -- Central America.; Medical care -- China.; Medical care -- Philippines.; Medicine.; Newspaper clippings.; Philippines -- Politics and government -- 1898-1935.; Philippines -- Social conditions -- 1898-1935.; Physicians -- United States.
- I. Correspondence
  - "Milkettes"
  - "The News Bag"
  - Aaron, Charles S
    Scope and Contents note
    General note
    See: See also:
  - Aaron, Hans C
  - Abbadie, Michael
  - Abbadie, Mrs. J
  - Abbott Laboratories
  - Abbott, N C
  - Abbott, Proctor & Paine
  - Abraham, Hans
  - Abrams, Al, Associates
  - Abriol, R
  - Academy of Medicine
  - Academy of Tropical Medicine
  - Acker, Stephen
  - Ackerman, Sara
  - Ackerson, Henry E
  - Acme Pump and Tank Corporation
  - Adam, Mrs. Rose B
  - Adams, Doris N
  - Adams, Louis
  - Adams, Mrs. Eugene G
  - Adams, Myrtle Hill
  - Adams, Queenie
  - Adams, Taylor
  - Admiral Oriental Line
  - Advertising Club of New York
  - Aero Spark Plug Company
  - Affleck, Benjamin F
  - Africa Bureau
  - Ager, Louis C.
  - Aguilar, E D
  - Ahern, Mrs. George P
  - Ahlers, O U
  - Ahrens
  - Aikens, Sidney
  - Aker, James C
  - Alabama, Department of Health
  - Albrecht, Frances
  - Albrecht, Mrs. Ralph G
  - Albrich, Edwin
  - Albright, Virginia L
  - Alco Valve Co.
  - Alcoholism
  - Aldrich, Donald B
  - Alexander, Durand C
  - Alexander, Mrs. Durand
  - Alexander, Mrs. M K
  - Alexay, Edward J
  - Alfonso, Victor
  - Alford, Mrs. J M
  - Alhambra, J Z
  - Alison, Mildred
  - Alkalol Company
  - Allan, Bessie
  - Allan,C W
  - Allegheny County (Pa.) General Health Council
  - Allen
  - Allen, Jewel
  - Allen, Mrs. D
  - Allen, Philip D
  - Allen, Thomas Dyer
  - Allen, W W III
  - Allison, W Theodore
  - Allport, Alexander W
  - Alma Julia, Sister
  - Aloe, A S ,Company
  - Alox Corporation
  - Alpers, Bernard J
  - Altan, Laura
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters
  - American Academy of Industrial Physicians and Surgeons
  - American Academy of Medicine
  - American Academy of Tropical Medicine
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science
  - American Association of Industrial Physicians and Surgeons
    See: Conferences
  - American Automobile Association
  - American Booksellers Association
  - American Bottlers of Carbonated Beverages
  - American Brake Shoe and Foundry Co.
  - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China
  - American Can Co.
  - American Cancer Society.
  - American College Girl
  - American College of Surgeons
  - American Committee for Chinese War Orphans
  - American Committee for Christian Refugees
  - American Cookery
  - American Council of St. Luke's International Medical Centre
  - American Die and Tool Co.
  - American Dietetic Association
  - American Express Company
  - American Federation of Medical Centers
  - American Film Center, Inc.
  - American Foundation for Tropical Medicine
  - American Foundation of Occupational Health, Directory of State and Local Industrial Hygiene Personnel
    See: Health Organizations in
  - American Geographical Society
  - American Hard Rubber Co.
  - American Heart Association, Inc.
  - American Heritage
  - American Hinge Corp.
  - American Home Products Corp
  - American Hospital Association
  - American Industrial Hygiene Association
  - American Institute
  - American Institute of Mining and Metalurgical Engineers
  - American Jewish Congress
  - American Journal of Nursing
  - American Judicature Society
  - American Leprosy Association
  - American Magazine
  - American Medical Association Council on Industrial Health
  - American Medical Association on Industrial Health
  - American Medical Association.
  - American Mercury
    See: Mencken, H L, in:
  - American Mission to Lepers
  - American Museum of Health
  - American Museum of Hygiene
  - American National Council for Health Education of the Public
  - American Nurses Association
  - American Pharmaceutical Manufacturers Association
  - American Philosophical Society
  - American Platform Guild, Inc.
  - American Public Health Association
  - American Radiator and Standard Sanitary Corp.
  - American Red Cross
  - American Social Hygiene Association, Inc.
  - American Society of Civil Engineers
  - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers
  - American Society of Parasitologists
  - American Society of Tropical Medicine
  - American Telegraph and Telephone
  - American Tube Bending Co.
  - American University, Beirut
  - American Viscose Corp
  - American Woman's Club
  - Ames, Adelbert, Jr.
  - Amesse, John W
  - Amory, Copley
  - Amoss, Harold L.
  - Anaconda Wire & Cable Company
  - Anders, Howard S
  - Anderson, C August
  - Anderson, Dwight
  - Anderson, E R
  - Anderson, Frank
  - Anderson, Mrs. H W
  - Anderson, W P
  - Anderson, William F
  - Anderson-Parks, Ellen M
  - Andrews, E A
  - Angeles, Sixto de Los
  - Angevine, D Murray
  - Antilla Sugar Estates
  - Anti-Tuberculosis League of cleveland and Cuyahogs Counties
  - Antona, Annetta H
  - Apgar, H C
  - Appell, Laurel
  - Appleman, Leighton F
  - Appleton, Bert
  - Araujo, Rosalina Biazoli d
  - Arbury, Mary
  - Archer, Frank
  - Ardor, Garage
  - Arlington County, Va. Health Dept.
  - Armand, Pierre C
  - Armitage
  - Armour Company
  - Armstrong Cork Company
  - Armstrong, A J
  - Armstrong, C W
  - Armstrong, Donald B
  - Army and Navy Club
  - Army Industrial Hygiene Laboratory
  - Arnold, Lloyd
  - Aron, Hans C S
  - Arron Automatic Products Corp.
  - Artistic Card Co.
  - Aschner, Bernard
  - Ashton, Ann M
  - Ashville Mica Company
  - Associated Hospital Service of New York
  - Associated Industries of Alabama
  - Associated Industries of Cleveland
  - Associated Industries of Massachusetts
  - Associated Press
  - Association of Casualty and Surety Executives
  - Aswell, Edward C
  - Aszmann, F W
  - Atherton, Ray
  - Atlantic Basic Iron Works
  - Atlantic Refining Company.
  - Atlantic Zinc Works, inc.
  - Atlee, John L
  - Auchincloss, James C
  - Augustin, Caroline B
  - Auspitzer, Richard G
  - Austin,T
  - Australia. Department of Health
  - Autenriech, Olga
  - Author's League of America
  - Auto Electric Service Co., Ltd.
  - Automatic Canteen Co.
  - Automatic Stores, Inc.
  - Avengo, Louise
  - AWA Clubhouse
  - Aycock, W. Lloyd
  - Aye, Hans A
  - Ayer, Margaret
  - Ayer, N W and Son, Inc.
  - Babcock, Harold
  - Bach, Ernest
  - Bacheller, Anne
  - Backwinkel, Edyth
  - Badger, Cecilia
  - Baehr, George
  - Baganz, C N
  - Bagg, Aaron, Moore
  - Bailey, Charles A
  - Bailey, Harold James
  - Baker Company
  - Baker, Alonzo L
  - Baker, E H
  - Baker, J N
  - Baker, Keith
  - Baker, Pauline E
  - Baker, Timothy D
    See: John Hopkins University
  - Baker's Helper
  - Bakers Weekly
  - Baldwin Locomotive Works
  - Baldwin, Mrs. Czekna
  - Baldwin, Mrs. Hugh
  - Balfour, L G Co.
  - Balina, Pedro L
  - Ball, John H
  - Ballerstadt, Wända
  - Bally, Mrs. Meta
  - Bandler, Clarence G
  - Baney, Charles M
  - Bank of New York
  - Bannister, Mrs. Claudian
  - Bantung, J P
  - Barbour, Lilly H
  - Barckman, Lester
  - Barker, Creighton
  - Barker, Esther
  - Barksdale, Lane
  - Barkuus, Arne
  - Barlow, Claude H
  - Barlow, V J
  - Barna, Gay
  - Barnes Drill Co., Inc.
  - Barnes, Jeanne N
  - Barnes, M E
  - Barnes, Mrs. William E
  - Barnes, W. F. and John Co.
  - Barnitz, Wirt
  - Barns, Mrs. B R
  - Barnstable, (Mass.) County Health Dept.
  - Barnwell, Mary Gaston Foundation
  - Barre Wool Combing Co., LTD
  - Barrett, Mrs. John W
  - Barrows Biochemical Corporation
  - Barry, David W
  - Barry, J W
  - Barsel, Norman
  - Barton Salt Co.
  - Barton, Betsy
  - Barton, Lady Winifred
  - Bartsch, Paul
  - Bashein, Bus
  - Bass, Frederick
  - Bassador, A M
  - Bates, Margaret
  - Bates, Mrs. F J
  - Batten, Barton, Durstine & Osbourne, Inc.
  - Battista, Louis de
  - Baum, Seymour J
  - Baumer, Peter
  - Baumgartner, Leona
  - Baumstark, Manfred
  - Baumzweiger, Ignatius
  - Baxter, Don, Inc.
  - Baxter, Othel
  - Bayault, Pierre
  - Bayley, Gertrude
  - Bayne, Laura M
  - Bayuk, Cigars, Inc.
  - Beach-Russ, Co.
  - Beacon Milling Co. Inc.
  - Beaman, A Gaylord
  - Bean, William B
  - Beard, Mary
  - Beatty, Jerome
  - Beaver, H C
  - Beaver, Harry C
    See: Biographical Material, in:
  - Becker, Eugene H
  - Becker, Henry C
  - Beckwith, J W
  - Beedle, Virginia
  - Beeson-Faller-Reichert, Inc.
  - Beeuwkes, Henry
  - Begg, Florence M
  - Behr, Gertrude H
  - Behrend, Moses
  - Behrn, Helen
  - Belber, Carl J
  - Belding, L J
  - Beleveau, Albert
  - Belknap, Emma F
  - Bell, A E
  - Bell, A L
  - Bell, Helen C
  - Bell, William H
  - Belt, Elmer
  - Belton Dickinson & Co.
  - Bement, John
  - Bendix Aviation Corp.
  - Bendixon, Elizabeth B
  - Benedict, Sister Mary
  - Benjamin Franklin Hotel
  - Benl, G J
  - Bennett, Avila Hall
  - Bennett, MRS. R
  - Bennett, Pauline
  - Benson, H A
  - Benson, William
  - Bentnew, Fritz
  - Benton, Corning
  - Berarr McFadden Foundation
  - Bercovitz, Z
  - Berdy, M H
  - Berehmans, Sister M
  - Berkens, Conrad
  - Berkowitz, Walter J
  - Berkshire Farm for Boys
  - Berlin, Gabi
  - Berlo, A van
  - Berman, Joanne
  - Berman, Nathan
  - Bernard, Katherine C
  - Bernese Alps Milk Co.
  - Bernheim, Henry C
  - Bernstein, George H
  - Bero, J E
  - Berolzheimer, Edwin M
  - Berry Bros.
  - Berry, George Packer
  - Berry, Katherine F
  - Berry, Martha
  - Bertsche, C V
  - Bessemer, Mary A
  - Best Foods, Inc.
  - Bethlehem Steel Co.
  - Better Homes and Gardens
  - Beuf, Carlo
  - Bexar County Tubercolusis Association
  - Bianchi, Charles
  - Bierdeman, Gertrude R
  - Bigelow, Maurice A
  - Bigger, Mrs. J H
  - Bilbad Prison
    See: Outbreak of Plague in ....., in:
  - Billig Clinic
  - Binder, Carroll
  - Binford, Chapman H
  - Bintz, Alma
  - Biographical Abstracts
  - Biographical Encyclopedia of the World
  - Biondo, Cecile H
  - Birks, G F
  - Birmingham Industrial Health Council
  - Birmingham Slag Co.
  - Birnbaum & Co.
  - Birnbaum, F
  - Birth Control Federation of America, Inc.
  - Bisalski, E M
  - Bishop, Mrs. R Bartlett
  - Black, Constance
  - Black, Katherine
  - Blackburne, G
  - Blackett, Nancy
  - Blackman, Earle A
  - Blackman, Sidney W Jr.
  - Blackman, W C
  - Blair, E Shiras
  - Blakely, William H
  - Blaker Advertising Agency
  - Bland, P Brooke
  - Blane, Edith Wendell
  - Blank, Mack
  - Blank-deLong, Charlotte
  - Bloch, Walter M
  - Blodgett, G. S. Co., Inc.
  - Bloom, Charles S
  - Bloom, M S
  - Blue, Rupert
  - Bluestone, E M
  - Bobbett, E Clark
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company
  - Boccaccio, Mary
  - Bodman, Herbert L
  - Bodnar, Julius
  - Boebeck, Mrs. Harry I
  - Bogert & Happer, Inc.
  - Bohan, Owen W
  - Bolanz, Fred
  - Boles, Edgar H
  - Bollinger, James K
  - Bollinger-Heitz, Lydie
  - Bombay. Director of Health, Surgeon General
  - Bondreau, Frank G
  - Bonham, Frederick T
  - Bonham, Mrs. F T
  - Bonjean, M
  - Bonner, Jack
  - Bonsal, Stephen
  - Boone, William Dawson
  - Booth, Arthur Woodward
  - Borden Co.
  - Borsook, Henry
  - Boschen, William H
  - Bostex Oil Co.
  - Boston Herald Book Fair
  - Bottomley, Mrs. Marion Trotter
  - Boucher, Arline Britton
  - Bousios, Basil
  - Bowden, Mrs. Gordon T
  - Bowditch, Edward
  - Bowditch, Mrs. Edward
  - Bowe, Kay
  - Bowers, A B
  - Bowers, Carl F
  - Bowler, P D
  - Bowman, F B
  - Bowman, Helen
  - Bowman, Lawrence G
  - Bowns, Edward E
  - Boxer, Jay I
  - Boyce, William B
  - Boyd, Elizabeth Poole
  - Boyd, Mark F
  - Boyd, S Malissa
  - Boyer, Esther W
  - Boyer, G p
  - Boyer, Marion E
  - Brack School
  - Bradley, Preston
    Book Lecture on An American Doctor's Odyssey
  - Brady, Mrs. Nicholas
  - Brady, T C
  - Brady, Thomas
  - Braga, Dorothy
  - Brandman, R E
  - Brandt, Carl
  - Branham, Gilbert
  - Brauch, Herman H
  - Braun, Sara Elkin
  - Bravo, Julio
  - Breckenridge, Marvin
  - Breed, Mrs. R E
  - Breeze Corporations, Inc.
  - Brehm, Paul A
  - Brennan, James J
  - Brennan, V
  - Brewster, Kathleen
  - Bricker, Verna L
  - Bridge Metal Products Co., Inc.
  - Bridgeport, Conn. City Health Officer
  - Bridgeport, Conn. Gas Light Co.
  - Bridges, S Russell
  - Bridgford L R
  - Briercliffe, R (Ceylon)
  - Briercliffe, Sir Rupert
  - Brighton, E E
  - Brink, Vernon E
  - Brinkler,G H
  - Briscoe, Miriam Gilmore
  - Brist, George L
  - Bristol, Mark L
  - British Council
  - British Information Services
  - Britsch, L D
  - Broaddus, C A
  - Brock Candy Co.
  - Brockmann, L O
  - Brodie, Nathan N
  - Broerman, Betty Jane
  - Broh, H
  - Bronk, Detlev W.
  - Bronx Free Fellowship
  - Brooklyn Federation of Jewish Charities
  - Brooks, E A
  - Broude, Louise
  - Brouillette, J W
  - Brown, E W
  - Brown, Earle G
  - Brown, Ethel Zaring
  - Brown, H Tatnall, Jr.
  - Brown, Harold P
  - Brown, Harris, Stevens, Inc.
  - Brown, N W
  - Brown, Robert M
  - Brown, Robert W
  - Brown, William Adams
  - Brownell, John R
  - Brownfield, R L
  - Bruckmiller, Ora E
  - Bruckner, Mary McGee
  - Bruere, Henry
  - Bruzzo, Stanley
  - Bryan, Ray
  - Bryant, Lela
  - Brydges, Mrs. George W
  - Buch, Theodore
  - Buck, Pearl A
  - Buckingham, H S
  - Budoff, Lillian
  - Buell, Mrs. Ely
  - Buell, Raymond Leslie
  - Buffalo (NY) Convention and Tourist Bureau, Inc.
  - Building America
  - Bull, Harry A
  - Bullard, E. D., Co.
  - Bulmer, F M R
  - Bulova Watch Company
  - Bunch, J B
  - Bundy, Mrs. J A
  - Bunn, Mrs. F V
  - Burbank, Bernerd H
  - Burchell Products
  - Burden, William A M
  - Burdenski, Cordula
  - Burdick, Arthur
  - Bureau of Cooperative Medicine
  - Bureau of Insular Affairs
  - Burger & Cie
  - Burgess, Perry
  - Burggraf, Otto C
  - Burke, Katherine J
  - Burlingame, C Charles
  - Burnet, Etienne
  - Burnet, Marguerite
  - Burnet, W. E. & Co.
  - Burnett, Francis Lowell
  - Burnham, Carol McLane
  - Burns, H B
  - Burns, J
  - Burns, Philip J
  - Burr, Mr.
  - Burris, Barbara
  - Burrows, Peggy
  - Burrows, Samuel J
  - Burrows, Thomas w
  - Burrows, Victor G
  - Burton, Florence Slack
  - Bush, E R Jr.
  - Busher, Joyce E
  - Bushnell, George H
  - Buswell, Mary H
  - Buttram, Alice
  - Butts, Heber
  - Butts, Mrs. J. DeWitt
  - Butz, J Treichler
  - Byers, A. M. Co.
  - Byers, Jesse M
  - Byington, Lane
  - Byington, Mrs. Homer
  - Byrd, Jess McCarter
  - Byron, Robert J
  - Bysshe, Mrs. Stanley M
  - Cahill, Kevin M
  - Calderon, Fernando
  - Calderone, Frank A
  - Caldwell, Otis W
  - Calhoun County (Michigan) Health Department
  - California Bureau of Industrial Health
  - California Joint Immigration Committee
  - California Packing Corp.
  - California Packing Corp.
  - California Vegetable Concentrates, Inc.
  - California, University of
  - Calloway Mills
  - Calumet and Hella Consolidated Copper Co.
  - Calver, Homer N
  - Calver, Mrs. Homer
  - Calverley, Eleanor Taylor
  - Cambridge Tuberculosis and Health Association
  - Cameron, J Donald
  - Camous, Florence L E
  - Camp Fire Girls, Incorporated
  - Campbell Soup Co.
  - Campbell, Alfred S
  - Campbell, Carol H
  - Campbell, Carrie
  - Campbell, Guy Gibson
  - Campbell, Mary
  - Campbell, Meade
  - Campbell, Sandy
  - Campbell, William S
  - Campbell, Wyant & Cannon Foundry Co.
  - Canada Department of Labor
  - Canada Department of National Health and Welfare
  - Canada Department of Veterans Affairs
  - Canadian Manufacturers Association
  - Canby, Edmund
  - Canby, Henry S
  - Candee, R C
  - Canniff, F J
  - Canteen Food Service
  - Cantelmi, Anthony
  - Cantwell, Eva M
  - Cape, Jonathan
  - Capital Foundry Co.
  - Carbide & Carbon Chemical Corp.
  - Care, Inc.
  - Carey, Eben J
    See: Crile, George, in:
  - Carlin, Walter Jeffreys
  - Carlson, Anton j
    See: Vivisection in:
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York
  - Carolina Mills, Inc.
  - Caroline Medical Institute
  - Carpenter, Catherine
  - Carpenter, Evelyn M
  - Carpenter, Frank W
    See also: Sally Lucas Jean
  - Carpenter, Grace
  - Carpenter, Groo
  - Carpenter, Harve J
  - Carpenter, Marcia B
  - Carpenter, P J
  - Carr, Edith
  - Carrell, Eleanor Prescott
  - Carrier Corporation
  - Carroll, James F
  - Carslake, Sarah G
  - Carson, R Mc
  - Carswell, C H
  - Carter
  - Carter, R Franklin
  - Carter, T J
  - Carter,Edward C
  - Carvalho, Octavio de
  - Carver Hotel, Warren Pa.
  - Carver, Charles Andrews
  - Carver, Mrs.
  - Casari, Matilde Bucci
  - Case H G
  - Case, Elizabeth C
  - Case, F P
  - Case, Mrs. Clifford
  - Casey Walter J
  - Castillas
  - Castillo, Antonio du
  - Castonquay, Gertrude R
  - Catanzaro, Grace T
  - Caterpillar Tractor Company
  - Caulfield, Mary G
  - Causey, Mrs. C W
  - Cecil, Russell L
  - Ceco Steel Products Corporation
  - Celano, Marino
  - Century Association
  - Century Equipment Corporation
  - Cereal Institute, Inc.
  - Chace, Arthur F
  - Chadbourne, William M
  - Chadwick, Selma R
  - Chadwick, William G
  - Chaffee, Stephen E
  - Chaffin, Lawrence
  - Chamber of Commerce Bristol, Conn.
  - Chamber of Commerce of the the USA
  - Chamberlin, Jo H
  - Chambers, R M
  - Chamerich, Morris
  - Champion, Nina H
  - Chandler, Asa C
  - Chandler, C de F
  - Chandler, Loren Roscoe
  - Chang, Helen
  - Chapell, Mrs. Michael
  - Chapman Valve Mfg. Co.
  - Chapman, A G
  - Chapman, Dee
  - Chapman, F G
  - Chappell, Sidney L
  - Charner, Hilliard
  - Chase Manhattan Bank
  - Chase National Bank
  - Chase, Olga
  - Chatterji, S N
  - Cheever, Austin W
  - Cherepy, Beatrice
  - Cherry, W L
  - Chester, Helen
  - Chicago Extruded Metals Co.
  - Chicago Health Department
  - Chicago Industrial Health Association
    See also: Health Organizations, in:
  - Chicago Industrial Health Association
  - Chicago Medical Society
  - Chicago Medical Society, Evanston Branch
  - Chicago, University Round Table
  - Chidester, F. E.
  - Child, Townshend
  - Children's Hospital, Philadelphia
  - Children's War Service
  - China Aid Council
  - China Medical Association
  - China, Impressions of
  - Chinese Studies Institute
  - Chisholm, Elizabeth
  - Chittick, Henrietta A
  - Chossis, G
  - Christ, Michael
  - Christensen, Charles
  - Chrysler Corporation
  - Ciba Company
  - Cifaratta, Bonnie
  - Cincinnati Milling Machine Co.
  - Cincinnatti Gas & Electric Co. and Times
  - Circumnavitors Club
  - Citizens Cemetary Association
  - Citizen's Committee to Repeal Chinese Exclusion
  - City Club of New York
  - City Ice and Fuel co.
  - City News Publishing Co.
  - Civil Service of Canada
  - Clanny, William John
  - Clark, Dean
  - Clark, H W Sr.
  - Clark, William A, 2nd
  - Clausen, Henry C
  - Clayton, A Y
  - Clegg, Edna W
  - Cleland, Ralph E
  - Clement, J W Company
  - Cleveland Health Museum
  - Cleveland Industrial Union Council
  - Cleveland Plain Dealer
  - Cleveland Thayer Committee
  - Clifton, MRS. C B
  - Cline, Maud G
  - Clinics on Health of Industry
  - Clinton, Mrs. Delmar Smith
  - Close, Grace C
  - Clow, Harry M
  - Clow, James B & Sons
  - Cobb, Maude A
  - Cobb, William C
    See: Rockefeller Foundation, Inc., in:
  - Coca-Cola Bottling Co.
  - Cochran Junior High School
  - Cochrane, R G
  - Cochrun, Col.
  - Coe, Mrs. Herbert W
  - Coetzee, A M
  - Cohen, Arthur A
  - Cohen, Harold H
  - Cohn,Alfred E
  - Colbough, Charles
  - Cole, Elbert C
  - Cole, Harold N
  - Cole, W C
  - Coleburn, George, W., Laboratory
  - Coleman Lamp and Stove Co.
  - Coleman, LeRoy
  - Coleman, Lois R
  - Colgan, John A
  - College of Physicians and Surgeons of New York
  - Colliers.
  - Collingswood, Charles
  - Collins, Alan C
  - Collins, Mrs. E C
  - Colman, Roger
  - Colonial Bank and Trust Company
  - Colorado. Division of Public Health
  - Colton, Sara
  - Columbia Machine Works, Inc.
  - Columbia University
  - Columbia University Club
  - Columbia University Press.
  - Columbus Coated Fabrics Corp.
  - Colvin, Mrs. Carl
  - Comfort, N C
  - Commentator
  - Commerce and Industry Association of New York
  - Commercial Solvents Corporation.
  - Commercial Solvents Corporation.
  - Committee for the Annual Observance of the Bill of Rights
  - Committee on Air Pollution Control
  - Committee on Industrial Health and Safety
  - Committee on the Nutrition of Industrial Workers
  - Commonwealth Fund
  - Community Vocational Service
  - Conklin, Mae
  - Conklin, T. E., Brass and Cooper Co., Inc.
  - Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station
  - Connecticut Cancer Society, Inc.
  - Connecticut General Life Ins. Co.
  - Connecticut light and Power Company
  - Connecticut State Medical Journal
  - Connecticut State Park and Forest Commission
  - Connecticut.Department of Health
  - Connecticut.Department of Motor Vehicles
  - Connell, J C
  - Connor, William H
  - Conrad, Mrs. George W
  - Conradi, May King
  - Considine, Robert
  - Consolidated Edison Co. of New York
  - Consumer Interests Committee
  - Consumers Union
  - Contra Costa (Calif.) Public Health Association
  - Converse, Mildred Bullit
  - Cook, David C Jr.
  - Cook, Frances Kerr
  - Cook, Roy B
  - Cook, Thomas, & Son.
  - Cooley, J B
  - Cooley,Alice
  - Cooper, Alice Page
  - Cooper, Grace
  - Cooperative league of the USA
  - Coopernail, George p
  - Corbin, Edith Patten
  - Cordley & Hayes
  - Cornell University
  - Cornish, Louis C
  - Cornwell,Mrs. Dean
  - Corrasala
  - Correll, Malcolm
  - Corser, Ruth
  - Cortland Free Library